Guide to the Yale Repertory Theatre and Yale School of Drama Ephemera Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Yale Repertory Theatre and Yale School of Drama Ephemera Collection
1925-2010
DRA 37
Yale University Arts Library
8.75
(22 boxes)
This collection contains ephemera pertaining to Yale Repertory Theatre, Yale School of Drama, and other undergraduate theater organizations at Yale University.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Yale Repertory Theatre and Yale School of Drama Ephemera Collection was housed in the former Drama Library until its transfer to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library in 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of the following ephemeral materials pertaining to Yale Repertory Theatre (YRT) and Yale School of Drama (YSD): theater programs; course catalogues; brochures; posters; student registration lists and directories; rehearsal, production, and course schedules; cast lists; commencement programs; newsletters; clippings; league scenes programs; holiday cards; and materials relating to guest performances sponsored by YRT and YSD. The collection also includes a few items pertaining to the Yale Dramatic Association (also known as the Dramat) and other undergraduate theater organizations and performances.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically by year, then month and day. Materials with year-only information are filed after items arranged by month and day. Notes have been provided for any folders containing materials other than YRT and YSD ephemera.
Printed ephemera; Theater programs; Yale Repertory Theatre; Yale School of Drama; Yale University. Dramatic Association
- Box listing
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1925-1926; 7 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1926-1927; Folder 2: 10 items; Folder 3: 10 items (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1927-1928; Folder 4: 10 items; Folder 5: 4 items (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1928-1929; 6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1929-1930; 8 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1930-1931; 8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1931-1933; 10 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1933-1934; 9 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1934-1935; 8 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1935-1937; 10 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1937-1940; 12 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1940-1942; 11 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1942-1945; 12 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1945-1947; 10 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1947-1948; 12 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1948-1949; Folder 18: 9 items; Folder 19: 6 items (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1949-1950; 15 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1950-1951; Folder 21: 10 items; Folder 22: 8 items (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1951-1952; Folder 23: 10 items; Folder 24: 7 items (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
    Scope and Contents
    Folder 24 includes a Dramat program.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1952-1953; Folder 25: 10 items; Folder 26: 6 items (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1953-1954; 15 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Folder 27 includes a Dramat program.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1954-1955; Folder 28: 9 items; Folder 29: 9 items (Box 2, Folder 28-29)
    Folder 29 includes a Dramat program.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1955-1956; 15 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1956-1957; 11 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1957-1958; 14 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Folder 32 includes Dramat programs.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1958-1959; 14 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Folder 33 includes Dramat materials.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1959-1960; 9 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1960-1961; Folder 35: 10 items; Folder 36: 10 items (Box 2, Folder 35-36)
    Folder 36 includes Dramat programs and a brochure.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1961-1962; Folder 37: 10 items; Folder 38: 11 items (Box 3, Folder 37-38)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1962-1963; Folder 39: 10 items; Folder 40: 10 items; Folder 41: 10 items (Box 3, Folder 39-41)
    Folder 41 includes Dramat materials and a brochure for the Yale Drama Festival. See also a hand-written note to F. Curtis Canfield on verso of one sheet of the production schedule.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1963-1964; Folder 42: 10 items; Folder 43: 8 items; Folder 44: 10 items (Box 3, Folder 42-44)
    Folder 44 includes Dramat and Yale Drama Festival materials.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1964-1965; Folder 45: 11 items; Folder 46: 10 items; Folder 47: 7 items; Folder 48: 6 items (Box 3, Folder 45-48)
    Folder 48 includes Dramat and Yale Drama Festival materials.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1965-1966; Folder 49: 11 items; Folder 50: 9 items; Folder 51: 10 items; Folder 52: 6 items (Box 4, Folder 49-52)
    Folder 52 includes Dramat and Yale Drama Festival materials.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1966-1967; Folder 53: 10 items; Folder 54: 12 items (Box 4, Folder 53-54)
    Folder 54 includes Dramat and Yale Drama Festival materials.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1967-1968; Folder 55: 11 items; Folder 56: 6 items (Box 4, Folder 55-56)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1968-1969; Folder 57: 11 items; Folder 58: 12 items (Box 4, Folder 57-58)
    Folder 57 includes a speech by Robert Brustein given to the School of Drama, minutes from a faculty meeting, and a memo on student discipline. Folder 58 includes materials relating to the cancellation of Sam Shepard's Operation Sidewinder and a Yale Drama Festival brochure.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1969-1970; Folder 59: 11 items; Folder 60: 13 items (Box 4, Folder 59-60)
    Folder 60 includes a Dramat program.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1970-1971; Folder 61: 11 items; Folder 62: 10 items; Folder 63: 10 items; Folder 64: 7 items (Box 5, Folder 61-64)
    Folder 63 includes a commencement address by Robert Brustein.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1971-1972; Folder 65: 10 items; Folder 66: 10 items (Box 5, Folder 65-66)
    Folder 66 includes Dramat programs.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1972-1973; Folder 208: 11 items; Folder 209: 10 items; Folder 210: 10 items (Box 16, Folder 208-210)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1973-1974; Folder 211: 12 items; Folder 212: 9 items; Folder 213: 8 items; Folder 214: 6 items (Box 16, Folder 211-214)
    Folder 212 includes a commencement address by Robert Brustein. Folder 214 includes a program and clipping from a Yale undergraduate production.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1974-1975; Folder 215: 9 items; Folder 216: 8 items; Folder 217: 6 items (Box 16, Folder 215-217)
    Folder 217 includes Dramat programs and programs from performances given during the Fourth International Congress on Enlightenment.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1975-1976; Folder 218: 10 items; Folder 219: 10 items (Box 16, Folder 218-219)
    See also Box 17.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1975-1976; Folder 220: 10 items; Folder 221: 11 items (Box 17, Folder 220-221)
    See also Box 16.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1976-1977; Folder 222: 10 items; Folder 223: 10 items; Folder 224: 9 items; Folder 225: 10 items; Folder 226: 9 items (Box 17, Folder 222-226)
    Folder 226 includes Dramat materials.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1977-1978; Folder 227: 11 items; Folder 228: 10 items; Folder 229: 10 items; Folder 230: 9 items; Folder 231: 5 items (Box 17, Folder 227-231)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1978-1979; Folder 232: 11 items; Folder 233: 10 items; Folder 234: 7 items; Folder 235: 13 items (Box 18, Folder 232-235)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1979-1980; Folder 67: 11 items; Folder 68: 10 items; Folder 69: 12 items (Box 5, Folder 67-69)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1980-1981; Folder 70: 12 items; Folder 71: 10 items; Folder 72: 10 items; Folder 73: 10 items; Folder 74: 7 items (Box 5, Folder 70-74)
    Folder 73 includes a letter to patrons regarding cuts to the National Endowment for the Arts (NEA). Folder 74 includes Dramat materials.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1981-1982; Folder 75: 12 items; Folder 76: 10 items; Folder 77: 9 items; Folder 78: 13 items (Box 6, Folder 75-78)
    Folder 78 includes Dramat programs and an interview with Louise Guay.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1982-1983; Folder 79: 14 items; Folder 80: 11 items; Folder 81: 11 items; Folder 82: 10 items (Box 6, Folder 79-82)
    Folder 82 includes a Dramat program.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1983-1984; Folder 83: 12 items; Folder 84: 10 items; Folder 85: 10 items; Folder 86: 16 items (Box 6, Folder 83-86)
    Folder 86 includes a Dramat program and a poster for a Yale Theatre Studies department colloquium. See also Box 18 for oversize materials dated 1983-1984.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1983-1984 (Box 18, Folder 237)
    See also Box 6 for regularly sized materials dated 1983-1984.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1984-1985; Folder 87: 14 items; Folder 88: 10 items; Folder 89: 11 items; Folder 90: 9 items; Folder 91: 14 items (Box 7, Folder 87-91)
    Folder 87 includes a Theatre for the Nuclear Freeze benefit poster. Folder 90 includes materials relating to the Yale Salute to Cole Porter benefit. Folder 91 includes a Dramat poster and materials from Yale undergraduate productions.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1985-1986; Folder 92: 11 items; Folder 93: 11 items; Folder 94: 11 items; Folder 95: 15 items (Box 7, Folder 92-95)
    Folder 94 includes materials relating to the Yale School of Drama 60th Anniversary Celebration. Folder 95 includes Dramat programs.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1986-1987; 9 (Box 7, Folder 96)
    See also Box 8.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1986-1987; Folder 97: 10 items; Folder 98: 9 items; Folder 99: 12 items; Folder 100: 8 items (Box 8, Folder 97-100)
    See also Box 7.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1987-1988; Folder 101: 12 items; Folder 102: 10 items; Folder 103: 10 items; Folder 104: 10 items (Box 8, Folder 101-104)
    Folder 101 includes materials pertaining to the Yale Repertory Theatre AIDS benefit.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1988-1989; Folder 105: 14 items; Folder 106: 11 items (Box 8, Folder 105-106)
    See also Box 9.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1988-1989; Folder 107: 10 items; Folder 108: 14 items (Box 9, Folder 107-108)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1989-1990; Folder 109: 9 items; Folder 110: 15 items; Folder 111: 10 items; Folder 112: 14 items (Box 9, Folder 109-112)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1990-1991; Folder 113: 10 items; Folder 114: 10 items (Box 9, Folder 113-114)
    Folder 114 includes materials pertaining to the Lloyd Richards Chair benefit. See also Box 10..
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1990-1991; Folder 115: 12 items; Folder 116: 13 items; Folder 117: 12 items (Box 10, Folder 115-117)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1991-1992; Folder 118: 13 items; Folder 119: 10 items; Folder 120: 16 items (Box 10, Folder 118-120)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 1992-1993; Folder 121: 12 items; Folder 122: 10 items; Folder 123: 10 items; Folder 124: 7 items; Folder 125: 11 items (Box 10, Folder 121-125)
    Folder 125 includes a Dramat program. See also Box 18 for oversize programs for Shooting a Dream and The Duchess of Malfi.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1992-1993; 2 (Box 18, Folder 236)
    See also Box 10.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1993-1994; Folder 126: 11 items; Folder 127: 11 items; Folder 128: 12 items; Folder 129: 11 items (Box 11, Folder 126-129)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1994-1995; Folder 130: 11 items; Folder 131: 12 items; Folder 132: 10 items; Folder 133: 10 items; Folder 134: 12 items (Box 11, Folder 130-134)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1995-1996; 12 (Box 11, Folder 135)
    See also Box 12.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1995-1996; Folder 136: 10 items; Folder 137: 10 items; Folder 138: 11 items; Folder 139: 14 items (Box 12, Folder 136-139)
    See also Box 11.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1996-1997; Folder 140: 12 items; Folder 141: 10 items; Folder 142: 10 items; Folder 143: 10 items; Folder 144: 13 items (Box 12, Folder 140-144)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1997-1998; Folder 145: 14 items; Folder 146: 10 items; Folder 147: 14 items (Box 12, Folder 145-147)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1998-1999; Folder 148: 18 items; Folder 149: 13 items (Box 12, Folder 148-149)
    See also Box 13.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1998-1999; Folder 150: 10 items; Folder 151: 11 items (Box 13, Folder 150-151)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 1999-2000; Folder 152: 11 items; Folder 153: 11 items; Folder 154: 10 items; Folder 155: 8 items; Folder 156: 11 items (Box 13, Folder 152-156)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 2000-2001; Folder 157: 11 items; Folder 158: 13 items; Folder 159: 12 items; Folder 160: 10 items; Folder 161: 11 items (Box 13, Folder 157-161)
    See also Box 14.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 2000-2001; 10 (Box 14, Folder 162)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 2001-2002; Folder 163: 12 items; Folder 164: 11 items; Folder 165: 10 items; Folder 166: 11 items; Folder 167: 13 items (Box 14, Folder 163-167)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 2002-2003; Folder 168: 12 items; Folder 169: 10 items; Folder 170: 10 items; Folder 171: 7 items; Folder 172: 8 items (Box 14, Folder 168-172)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 2003-2004; Folder 173: 10 items; Folder 174: 10 items; Folder 175: 10 items (Box 14, Folder 173-175)
    See also Box 15.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 2003-2004; Folder 176: 10 items; Folder 177: 10 items; Folder 178: 13 items (Box 15, Folder 176-178)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 2004-2005; Folder 179: 11 items; Folder 180: 11 items; Folder 181: 10 items; Folder 182: 13 items; Folder 183: 10 items (Box 15, Folder 179-183)
    Folder 183 includes a Dramat program.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 2005-2006; Folder 184: 11 items; Folder 185: 11 items; Folder 186: 9 items; Folder 187: 12 items (Box 15, Folder 184-187)
    See also Box 19.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 2005-2006; 8 (Box 19, Folder 188)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 2006-2007; Folder 189: 13 items; Folder 190: 12 items; Folder 191: 10 items; Folder 192: 11 items; Folder 193: 10 items (Box 19, Folder 189-193)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 2007-2008; Folder 194: 9 items; Folder 195: 16 items; Folder 196: 9 items; Folder 197: 10 items; Folder 198: 10 items (Box 19, Folder 194-198)
    See also Box 20.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera*, 2007-2008; 5 (Box 20, Folder 199)
    Folder 199 includes a Dramat program and materials from other Yale undergraduate productions. See also Box 19.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 2008-2009; Folder 200: 13 items; Folder 201: 10 items; Folder 202: 10 items; Folder 203: 12 items; Folder 204: 13 items; Folder 205: 11 items; Folder 206: 10 items; Folder 207: 7 items (Box 20, Folder 200-207)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 2009-2010; 1 (Box 20, Folder 208)
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 2009-2010; Day, Belene (Box 21)
    Includes promotional materials for the 2009-2010 YSD curriculum press releases; 2009-2010 alumni magazine; 2009 Yale Summer Cabaret; 2010 Yale Summer Cabaret; 2009-2010 Yale School of Drama productions; 2009-2010 No Boundaries (WPP); and 2009-2010 Yale Repertory Theatre productions.
  - YRT and YSD ephemera, 2010-2013 (Box 22)
    Includes promotional materials for the 2010-2011 and 2012-2013 seasons of both the Yale School of Drama and the Yale Repertory Theatre.
- 2017 addition, 1992-1998
  - The Colored Museum, Dec 1992; 16 (Box 23, Folder 212)
    Includes photographs, press releases, flyer, and event programs.
  - As You Like It, 1994-02-1994-03; 10 (Box 23, Folder 214)
    Includes photographs and flyers.
  - The Marriage of Figaro / Figaro Gets a Divorce, 1994-12; 12 (Box 23, Folder 216)
    Includes flyers and photographs for Marriage of Figaro / Figaro Gets a Divorce; Postcarsds for The Good Person of Szechwan.
  - Le Cirque Invisible, 1995-10-1995-11; 4 (Box 23, Folder 217)
    Includes program, flyer, and photographs.